Rainy Schaberg



SOFTWARE ENGINEER IN ST. LOUIS, MO

EMAIL rainy.schaberg@gmail.com **GITHUB** Rainy Schaberg's GitHub | **LINKEDIN** Rainy Schaberg's LinkedIn

I am a lifelong autodidact with a highly adaptive approach to growth and learning. I lead with unwavering values in the importance of research-based best practices used in conjunction with the creative mind to develop innovative solutions.

LANGUAGES		FRAMEWORKS		DATABASES	TOOLS
 JavaScript 	• Java	• Spring	 Angular 	• MySQL	• Git
 TypeScript 	• HTML5/CSS3	 Hibernate 	Jasmine		• IntelliJ IDEA
• SQL		• JUnit			 Visual Studio Code

WORK EXPERIENCE

Business Process Improvement Specialist - Social Support, Block, Inc. - Cash App, St. Louis, MO, April 2023 - Present

• Research and identify key areas of opportunity for process improvement for social media support channels, provide consultation to stakeholders and leadership.

Customer Experience Improvement Specialist - Messaging Support, Block, Inc. - Cash App, St. Louis, MO, December 2022 - April 2023

• Collaborate with Integration Services, Learning & Performance Optimization and Project Management Operations to develop scalable, short-term trust-building solutions for advocates.

Learning & Performance Optimization Specialist - Continuous Learning, Block, Inc. - Cash App, St. Louis, MO, June 2021 - December 2022

- Design, develop and implement comprehensive virtual learning materials for an international audience of 150+ advanced support coaches and 300+ customer success advocates.
- Design, code, test and maintain dynamic performance optimization tools using Text Blaze with an average of ~1,200,000 advocate usages per month.

Customer Success Advocate, Square for Restaurants DRI, Block, Inc. - Square, St. Louis, MO, April 2019 – June 2021

 Provide voice-based tech support for customers using Square for Restaurants app, serve as direct liaison between product manager and customer success.

PROJECT EXPERIENCE

Text Blaze Workflow Assistant — Cash App

- Developed a proof-of-concept of an interactive Workflow Assistant to address advocate learning needs.
- Prototype was included in last year's year-end recommendations to leadership.
- Successfully advocated for adoption of pilot as an OKR set to begin Q3 2023.

EDUCATION

LaunchCode, LC101 Full Stack Programming Course — 2023 **The Evergreen State College**, B.A.B.S. Pre-Medicine, Fine Art